Guide to the Claude McKay Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1923-90; Series I; 3.34; (8 boxes)
  - GENERAL
    - Thompson, Anita, 1930-31 (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Thorne, Anthony, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 206)
    - Thurman, Wallace, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 207)
    - "U" General, 1928-48, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 208)
      Includes letter from U.S. Dept. of State to James Weldon Johnson
    - United States. Dept. of Labor, 1928-39 (Box 7, Folder 209)
    - United States. Works Progress Administration (N.Y.), 1936-37 (Box 7, Folder 210)
      See also: Federal Writers' Project (N.Y.), Box 3, folders 78-79
    - "V" General, 1935 Feb 28 (Box 7, Folder 211)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1934-49 (Box 7, Folder 212-214)
      Includes letter to Ruth Hope McKay Virtue and book jacket to Harlem: Negro Metropolis
    - Virtue, Ruth Hope McKay, 1929-90 (Box 7, Folder 215-218)
      Includes correspondence with Frederick Black, the British Broadcasting Corporation, Bessie Childs, Nannie Clark, Carl Cowl and "Sid"
      See also: Oversize, Box 20, folder 619
    - Vogein, Pierre, 1932-40, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 219-221)
      Includes enclosures from A. Grosse and Pierre Marcel and review fragment
    - Voila, 1932-33 (Box 7, Folder 222)
      Includes letter to Georges Friedmann
    - "W" General, 1928-48 (Box 7, Folder 223-225)
    - Wagner, Jean, 1958 Jun 28 (Box 7, Folder 226)
    - Walrond, Eric, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 227)
    - Watson, James S., 1937-42 (Box 7, Folder 228)
    - Weinstock, Herbert
      See: Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., Box 8, folder 249
    - West, Dorothy, 1935, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 229)
    - White, Walter, 1933-39 (Box 7, Folder 230)
      Includes letters to Arthur Schomburg and Max Eastman
      See also: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Box 5, folder 154
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1937-40 (Box 7, Folder 231)
    - Wilson, Gladys W., 1928-35 (Box 7, Folder 232-233)
    - Work, 1944-48 (Box 7, Folder 234)
      See also: Marciniak, Ed, Box 5, folder 146
    - Wright, Ernest Hunter, 1937 Sep 11 (Box 7, Folder 235)
    - Yale University. Library, 1941 Oct (Box 7, Folder 236)
    - "Z" General, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 237)
      Includes letter from Curtis Zahn to Ammon Hennacy
    - ----, Charlotte, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 238)
      Includes letters to Max Eastman
    - ----, Lucien, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 239)
    - Unidentified, 1924-44, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 240-242)
    - Empty envelopes, 1926-48, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 243-247)
  - PUBLISHERS
    - "A" General, 1934, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 248)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1947 (Box 8, Folder 249)
    - "B" General, 1925, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 250)
    - Bantam Books, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 251)
    - "C" General, 1941-47 (Box 8, Folder 252)
    - "D" General, 1947-50 (Box 8, Folder 253)
    - Dodd, Mead & Company, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 254)
    - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1947-48 (Box 8, Folder 255)
      See also: George H. Doran Company, Box 8, folder 264
    - "E" General, 1948 Jun 25 (Box 8, Folder 256)
    - E. P. Dutton (Firm), 1940-48 (Box 8, Folder 257-260)
      Includes letters to Max Eastman and Claire Leonard
    - Éditions Rieder, 1927-34 (Box 8, Folder 261)
    - "F" General, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 262)
    - "G" General, 1938, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 263)
    - George H. Doran Company, 1926 Jan 28 (Box 8, Folder 264)
      See also: Doubleday and Company, Inc., Box 8, folder 255
    - "H" General, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 265)
    - Harcourt Brace & Company, 1934, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 266)
    - Harper & Brothers, 1927-48 (Box 8, Folder 267-270)
    - Henry Holt and Company, 1947-48 (Box 8, Folder 271)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 272)
    - "L" General, 1936-48 (Box 8, Folder 273)
    - Little, Brown & Company, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 274)
    - "M" General, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 275)
    - "P" General, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 276)
    - "R" General, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 277)
    - Random House (Firm), 1947 (Box 8, Folder 278)
    - Sheed and Ward (Firm), 1944 (Box 8, Folder 279)
    - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1933 Sep 12 (Box 8, Folder 280)
      Letter from Clifton Fadiman to Max Eastman
    - "V" General, 1947 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 281)
    - "W" General, 1947 Jan 23 (Box 8, Folder 282)
- Writings, 1922-85; Series II; 2.1; (5 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is organized into eight subseries and arranged alphabetically within each subseries by title or author.
  - ARTICLES, ESSAYS AND REPORTS
    - "Le capitalisme américain fait le loi," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 283)
    - "Claude McKay Versus Powell," printed version, New York Amsterdam News, 1937 Nov 6 (Box 9, Folder 284)
    - "Fourth Report to His Excellency Bernard J. Shiel," typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, 1945 Mar 15 (Box 9, Folder 285)
    - "The Free Masonic Order of Negroes in New York," typescript, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 286)
    - "Group Life and Literature," typescript carbon, corrected (Box 9, Folder 287)
    - "Lalla Shellah," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 288)
    - "Miss Allah," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 289)
    - "Negro Extinction or Survival," printed version, New York Amsterdam News, 1937 Nov 20 (Box 9, Folder 290)
    - "A Negro to His Critics," printed version, New York Herald Tribune, 1932 Mar 6 (Box 9, Folder 291)
    - "Negroes From New York in the U.S. Diplomatic Service"
      - Research notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 292)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 293)
    - "North African Triangle," printed version, The Nation, 1943 May 8 (Box 9, Folder 294)
    - "On the First Negroes Coming to America, Part 2," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 295)
    - "Picket Committee of the Citizen's League For Fair Play," galley proof, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 20, folder 620
    - [Reply to Article on Communist Party Control of Negro Workers], printed version, New York Amsterdam News, 1938 Sep 17 (Box 9, Folder 296)
    - "Report 5 to His Excellency Bernard J. Shiel," typescript, 1945, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 297)
    - "Right Turn to Catholicism," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 298)
    - "Schuyler Lashes... Like Mad Dog," printed version, The Pittsburgh Courier, 1937 Dec 4 (Box 9, Folder 299)
    - "Sixth Report to His Excellency Bernard J. Shiel," typescript and typescript carbon, 1945-47, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 300)
  - AUTOBIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION
    - "Statement by Mr. Claude McKay," typescript carbon, 1940 Nov 19 (Box 9, Folder 301)
  - BLURBS
    - Blurb for Abdul Hamid appearance, advertisement, printed version, 1935 Apr 8 (Box 9, Folder 302)
  - BOOKS
    - Banana Bottom
      - Reviews, 1933-34, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 303)
    - Banjo
      - Card, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 304)
      - Reviews, 1929-31, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 305)
        See also: Oversize, Box 20, folder 621
      - French edition
        - Reviews, 1931-32, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 306)
    - Gingertown
      - Reviews, 1932, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 307)
    - Harlem: Negro Metropolis
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 308-309)
      - Jacket blurb, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 310)
      - Reviews, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 311)
        See also: Oversize, Box 20, folder 622
    - Home to Harlem
      - Reviews, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 312-321)
        See also: Oversize, Box 20, folder 623
      - Reviews, 1928-29, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 322-324)
      - French edition ( Quartier noir )
        - Reviews, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 325)
    - A Long Way From Home
      - Outline, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 326)
      - Reviews, 1936-37, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 327)
    - My Green Hills of Jamaica
      - Research notes, holograph and typescript (Box 10, Folder 328)
      - Draft fragments, holograph, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 329)
      - Drafts, original, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 10, Folder 330-331)
      - Draft, revised, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 11, Folder 332-333)
      - Draft fragments, final, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 334)
    - "Romance in Marseille"
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 335)
  - NOTES AND NOTEBOOKS
    - Miscellaneous notes, holograph and typescript (Box 11, Folder 336)
    - Notebooks, holograph, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 337-339)
  - POETRY
    - "Adolescence," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 340)
    - "Africa," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 341)
    - "Aftermath," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 342)
    - "Alfonso, Dressing to Wait at Table," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 343)
    - "America," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 344)
    - "Baptism," typescript and typescript carbon (Box 11, Folder 345)
    - "Boomerang," typescript and typescript carbon (Box 11, Folder 346)
    - "The Catholic Church," drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 11, Folder 347)
    - "Christ Among the Dictators," drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 11, Folder 348)
    - "The City's Love," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 349)
    - "The Cycle"
      - Drafts, holograph, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 11, Folder 350-354)
      - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 11, Folder 355-356)
    - "Dawn in New York," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 357)
    - "December, 1919," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 358)
    - "The Desolate City," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 359)
    - "The Easter Flower," typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 11, Folder 360)
    - "Enslaved," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 361)
    - "Exhortation: Summer, 1919," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 362)
    - "Faith"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 363)
      - Printed version, Catholic Worker, 1946 Jan (Box 12, Folder 364)
    - "For Peace," drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 12, Folder 365)
    - Harlem Shadows
      - Book jacket, [1922] (Box 12, Folder 366)
    - "Harlem Shadows," typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 367)
    - "Home Thoughts," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 368)
    - "Homing Swallows," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 369)
    - "Hospital Patient," typescript carbon, 1938 Apr (Box 12, Folder 370)
    - "I Turn to God," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 371)
    - "If We Must Die"
      - Drafts, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 12, Folder 372)
      - Printed version, [ Mullai Charam ?], 1990 Mar (Box 12, Folder 372a)
        Includes letter from S. S. Kumar to Ruth Hope McKay Virtue on verso
    - "In Bondage," typescript carbon (Box 12, Folder 373)
    - "Look Within" printed version, Catholic Worker, 1945 Jan (Box 12, Folder 374)
    - "The Lynching," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 375)
    - "The Middle Ages," printed version, Catholic Worker, 1946 May (Box 12, Folder 376)
    - "My Mother," typescript and typescript carbon (Box 12, Folder 377)
    - "Negro Dancers," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 378)
    - "The New Day," drafts, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 379)
    - "New Poems"
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1935 Feb 2 (Box 12, Folder 380)
      - Drafts, "Cities," typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 12, Folder 381-382)
      - Drafts, "The Years Between," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 383)
      - Drafts, "The Clinic," typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 12, Folder 384)
    - "North and South," typescript carbon (Box 12, Folder 385)
    - "On Broadway," typescript carbon and photocopy (Box 12, Folder 386)
    - "On the Road," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 387)
    - "Outcast," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 388)
    - "The Pagan Isms," drafts, holograph, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 12, Folder 389)
    - "The Plateau," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 390)
    - "Russian Cathedral"
      - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 391)
      - Printed version, Catholic Interracialist, 1951 Sep (Box 12, Folder 392)
        See also: "St. Isaac's Church Petrograd"
    - "St. Isaac's Church Petrograd," typescript and typescript carbon (Box 12, Folder 393)
      See also: "Russian Cathedral"
    - "Saint Meinrad," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 394)
    - The Selected Poems of Claude McKay
      - Drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 12, Folder 395)
      - Draft, "Collected Poems," typescript carbon, corrected, 1953 Mar 4 (Box 12, Folder 396)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 397)
      - Galley proof, 1950 Mar 23
        See: Oversize, Box 20, folder 624
      - Galley proof, with printer's annotations, 1952 Jul
        See: Oversize, Box 20, folder 625
      - Book jacket, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 398)
      - Publicity material, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 399)
    - "A Song of Birth," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 400)
    - "Songs of Morocco," drafts, holograph, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 13, Folder 401)
    - "Sonnets," printed version, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 402)
    - "The Spanish Needle," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 403)
    - "Tiger"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 404)
      - Printed version, Catholic Worker, 1946 Jan (Box 13, Folder 405)
    - "The Tired Worker," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 406)
    - "To One Coming North," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 407)
    - "Transient," holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 408)
    - "Truth"
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 409)
      - Printed version, Catholic Worker, 1946 Jan (Box 13, Folder 410)
    - "When Dawn Comes to the City," drafts, typescript carbon (Box 13, Folder 411)
    - "The Wild Goat," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 412)
    - "Wild May," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 413)
    - "The Wise Men of the East," drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 13, Folder 414)
    - "The Word," drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 415)
    - Unidentified, 1944 Nov, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 416)
  - STORIES
    - "Dinner in Douarnenez"
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 417)
      - Printed version, with proofreader's annotations, The Literary Half- Yearly, 1985 Jul (Box 13, Folder 418)
    - Trial by Lynching (Mysore: Institute of Commonwealth and American Studies and English Language), 1989 (Box 13, Folder 418a)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Blary, Liliane
      - "Claude McKay and Black Nationalist Idealogies," printed version, Myth and Ideology in American Culture, 1977 Jan 5 (Box 13, Folder 419)
    - Catholic Youth Organization
      - Voice, 1944 Nov (Box 13, Folder 420)
    - Conroy, Sister Mary James
      - "Claude McKay," abstract, printed version from Disseration Abstracts, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 421)
    - Cooper, Wayne
      - "A Black Briton Comes 'Home': Claude McKay in England, 1920," article, printed version, Race, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 422)
      - "Claude McKay and the New Negro of the 1920s," typescript, corrected, 1964 Nov 17 (Box 13, Folder 423)
      - "McKay, Claude," biography, printed version, Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 424)
    - "A Glimmer of Their Own Beauty: Black Sounds of the Twenties," printed version, 1971, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 425)
      Includes letter from Bill Schenck to Donald Gallup
    - Hughes, Langston
      - "Broadcast to the West Indies," [radio broadcast?], typescript carbon, inscribed, [1943?] (Box 13, Folder 426)
      - "Claude McKay," review, typescript, inscribed, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 427)
    - Hugo, Victor
      - "Demain, dès l'aube," poem, clipping (Box 13, Folder 428)
    - Johnson, Georgia Douglas Camp
      - "The Return," poem, printed card, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 429)
    - Johnson, James Weldon
      - "Claude McKay," biography, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 430)
    - Kaempffert, Waldemar
      - "The Play's the Thing," article, printed version, Tomorrow, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 431)
    - Keating, Mary Jerdo
      - "Claude McKay," review, printed version, Catholic Interracialist, 1951 Sep (Box 13, Folder 432)
        Includes poem "White Houses"
    - Kemp, Ira F.
      - "The Case of the People of Harlem Against Bella Restaurant," open letter, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 433)
    - McKay Claude
      - "A Sunday Pitch," article, printed version, Nation, 1962 Dec 1 (Box 13, Folder 434)
      - "A Subtle Propagandist, letter to the editor, printed version, The Times, [1930?] (Box 13, Folder 435)
    - Reinders, Robert C.
      See: Cooper, Wayne, Box 13, folder 422
    - Schomburg Collection of Negro Literature and History
      - "The Negro: A Selected Bibliography," printed version, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 436)
    - Smith, Lillian E.
      - "Along Their Way," article, printed version, The North Georgia Review, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 437)
    - Sully Prudhomme
      - "L'Ideal," poem, clipping, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 438)
    - Van Jackson, Wallace
      - "The Countee Cullen Memorial Collection at Atlanta University," article, printed version, Crisis, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 439)
    - Van Vechten, Carl
      - "The J. W. Johnson Collection at Yale," article, printed version, Crisis, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 440)
    - Virtue, Ruth Hope McKay
      - "A Christmas Scene," poem, holograph, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 441)
      - Notebook, holograph, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 442)
      - Notebook of poems, typescript and holograph, corrected, 1938-39 (Box 13, Folder 443)
      - Research notes, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 444)
    - Wibecan, Ken
      - "An understanding daughter looks into the heart of a poet," biography, printed version, 1985 Feb 25 (Box 13, Folder 444a)
- Personal Papers, 1853-1989; Series III; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series III, Personal Papers, is organized into eight subseries.
  - BOOKS
    - Bible, [1853 Jul?] (Box 14, Folder 445)
    - The imitation of Christ (New York: Harper & Brothers), 1941 (Box 14, Folder 446)
    - Kuczynski, Jürgen, Germany's economic position (London: Germany Today), [1938?] (Box 14, Folder 447)
    - Shakespeare, William, Tragedy of Othello (London: J.M. Dent), 1900 (Box 14, Folder 448)
    - Stedman, Joseph F., My Sunday missal (Brooklyn: Confraternity of the Precious Blood), [1942?] (Box 14, Folder 449)
  - CLIPPINGS
    - Appearances, 1928-37, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 450)
    - Awards and Prizes, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 451)
    - Biographies, 1928, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 452)
    - Brief mentions, 1928-30, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 453)
    - General interest articles on McKay, 1929-47, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 454)
    - Interviews and Profiles, 1934-48, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 455)
      See also: Oversize, Box 20, folder 626
    - Literary references in English, German and Russian, 1928-52, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 456)
    - Obituaries in English and Spanish, 1948, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 457)
  - FINANCIAL AND LEGAL RECORDS
    - Bank books, 1935-43, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 458)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1925-47, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 459-463)
    - Contracts
      - E.P. Dutton (Firm), 1939 Dec 11 (Box 15, Folder 464)
      - Editorial Ercilla, 1940 Dec 5 (Box 15, Folder 465)
      - Harper & Brothers, 1930 Oct 29 (Box 15, Folder 466)
    - Currency
      - Estonian, 1919, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 467)
      - German, 1914, 1920 (Box 15, Folder 468)
      - Russian and Soviet, 1905-23 (Box 15, Folder 469)
    - Royalty statements
      - E.P. Dutton (Firm), 1939-46 (Box 15, Folder 470)
      - Harcourt, Brace & Company, 1925-29 (Box 15, Folder 471)
      - Harper & Brothers, 1928-35 (Box 15, Folder 472)
      - Lee Furman Inc., 1937-39 (Box 15, Folder 473)
    - Tax records, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 474)
    - War ration books, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 475)
    - Will, 1929 Jun 15 (Box 15, Folder 476)
  - INVITATIONS AND ANNOUNCEMENTS
    - Appearances by McKay, 1944, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 477)
    - Other events, 1942-49, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 478)
  - MATERIAL RELATING TO MCKAY'S DEATH AND BURIAL
    - Announcement, 1948 May (Box 15, Folder 479)
    - Bill and Check, 1948 May 28 (Box 15, Folder 480)
    - Certificate of death, 1948 May 24 (Box 15, Folder 481)
    - Condolences, 1948 May, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 482)
    - Deed, 1949 Apr 9 (Box 15, Folder 483)
    - Funeral registers, 1948 May (Box 16, Folder 484)
    - Thank you card, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 485)
    - Travelers Insurance Companies memo, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 486)
  - MEDICAL AND HEALTH RECORDS
    - Bills and Receipts, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 487)
    - Cards and Addresses (Box 16, Folder 488)
    - Certificate of Health, 1947 Jun 16 (Box 16, Folder 489)
    - Diet list, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 490)
    - Insurance documents, 1944, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 491)
    - Prescriptions, 1937, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 492)
  - POSTCARDS
    - Africa, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 493)
    - France, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 494)
    - Germany, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 495)
    - Luxembourg, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 496)
    - Russia, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 497)
    - Spain, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 498)
    - United States, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 499)
    - Other, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 500)
  - OTHER
    - Address Books and Cards, 1946, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 501-503)
    - Application for a Certificate of Arrival, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 504)
    - Beacon House publications list, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 505)
    - British Passport, 1932-37 (Box 16, Folder 506)
    - Calendar, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 507)
    - Certificate of Citizenship, 1940 Apr 13 (Box 16, Folder 508)
    - Certificate of Insurance, 1946 Jun 6 (Box 16, Folder 509)
    - Certificate of Literacy, 1940 Oct 9 (Box 16, Folder 510)
    - Change of address form, 1940 Nov (Box 16, Folder 511)
    - Crucifix, plaster and wood (damaged) (Box 16, Folder 512)
      Includes reference photos
    - Fragment from Kojo Tovalou Houénou's, w (Box 16, Folder 513)
    - L'Ivolution des métamorphoses et des métapsychoses de l'universe, 1923 Nov 27
      Includes inscription
    - Identification and membership cards, 1922-48 (Box 16, Folder 514)
    - Illustration, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 515)
    - List of Chicago restaurants "Where Negro Patrons Will Be Served Without Discrimination", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 516)
    - Lottery ticket, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 517)
    - Municipal Court Order to Vacate Premises, [1940?] Feb 1 (Box 16, Folder 518)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 519)
    - "Philatelic" souvenir of Booker T. Washington, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 520)
    - Poster of Soviet Communist Party members, 1923
      See: Oversize, Box 20, folder 627
    - Stamps, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 521)
    - Compact disc of Tyrone Jefferson's "Free Your Mind", 1989 (Box 16, Folder 522)
      Reference copy. Original held by Historical Sound Recordings.
    - Sunnyville Creative Colony brochure, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 523)
    - Telephone messages, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 524)
- Subject Files, 1927-43; Series IV; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series IV, Subject Files, is organized into two subseries: Individuals and Organizations, and Topical.
  - INDIVIDUALS AND ORGANIZATIONS
    - Chiang, May-ling Soong, 1943, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 525)
    - Trotsky, Leon, 1927-37, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 526)
    - United States. Works Progress Administration, 1936-38, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 527)
  - TOPICAL
    - Economics, 1930-35, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 528)
    - France, 1937-38, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 529)
    - Germany and Nazis, 1935, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 530)
    - Health and Medicine, 1928, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 531)
    - Jews and Judaism, 1935-38, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 532)
    - Labor, 1937-38, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 533)
      See also: Oversize, Box 20, folder 628
    - Literature, 1933-38, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 534)
    - Middle East, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 535)
    - Miscellaneous, 1928-38, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 536)